<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>News at DPML</title>
    <description>DPML News and Events.</description>
    <keywords>DPML, build, runtime, management, components, soa, java, composition</keywords>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="News &amp; Events">
    
      <subsection name="10 April 2007, DPML SDK 2.0.0 Release">
      
        <p>
        Version 2.0.0 is the latest production stable build of the DPML platform.  It 
        incorporates a number of important functional enhancements over the 1.X series brought
        about through an internal restructuring of the component deployment architecture.  The
        2.0.0 version has a structural dependency on the Java 1.6 platform.  Semantics 
        of component deployment such as Context definition remain backward compatible with 
        the 1.X series.  Internal APIs have changed relative to 1.X to better align with 
        draft JSR 277 module specifications.
        </p>

        <p>
        Key features incorporated into the 2.0.0 release include:
        </p>
        
        <ul>
          <li>JSR 277 readiness.</li>
          <li>Integral support for <tt>java.util.ServiceLoader</tt> as an basic extension mechansims.</li>
          <li>Support for plugable content type handlers via <tt>java.util.ServiceLoader</tt>.</li>
          <li>JMX management of the Transit resource management layer.</li>
          <li>Metro component model moved to a dedicated content type handler.</li>
          <li>Support for nested contect interface defintions.</li>
          <li>Context model suport for map datatypes.</li>
          <li>Support for uri fragment argument handling.</li>
          <li>Improved part interface semantics.</li>
          <li>Improved XSD namespace management.</li>
          <li>Package namespace updates to facilitate improved private class isolation.</li>
          <li>Comprehansive updates to tutorials and online documentation.</li>
          <li>Improvements to Station deployment metadata.</li>
          <li>Reduced platform footprint.</li>
        </ul>
        
      </subsection>
    
      <subsection name="3 December 2006, DPML SDK 1.1.0 Release">
      
        <p>
        The 1.1.0 release includes a number of small updates dealing with runtime
        support for Java 1.5 and 1.6.  The changes deal with memory management under
        1.5 and 1.6 that introduce requirements for a more restricted component
        decommissioning process.  Other changes include the addition of the support
        for symbolic property references inside part definitions declared at the
        level of a Depot project type declaration.
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="10 October 2006, DPML SDK 1.0.3 Maintenance Update">
      
        <p>
        The 1.0.3 update is a general maintenance release that incorporates 
        updates to the Transit artifact protocol handler and related Ant 
        tools.  The distribution also includes numerouse documentation 
        enhancements.
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="16 September 2006, DPML SDK 1.0.2 Maintenance Update">
      
        <p>
        The <a href="http://download.dpml.net/formal/sdk/1.0.2">1.0.2 release</a> 
        includes the resolution of a bug in the Transit console handler related 
        to the deployment of plugins from the command line.  Earlier versions did 
        not properly support plugins declaring a net.dpml.util.Logger constructor 
        argument instance.  The release also includes improvements to the console 
        info listing with additional version information for both console and 
        runtime resources.
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="11 August 2006, DPML SDK 1.0.1 Release">
      
        <p>
        Changes in this release include the addition of a new command-line option to the Depot build
        tool enabling a decimal version build policy together with some internal implementation 
        enhancements that enable the generation of a full DPML system build using the Depot build 
        system.  The decimal versioning option basically addresses functional requirements that arise
        when evaluating the impact of small changes on dependent systems.  In addition version 1.0.1
        introduces the ability within the DPML build to run the entire build under Depot (as opposed 
        to the earlier bootstrap+Depot build sequence).  With full Depot-based build sequencing in 
        place its now much easier to address subjects such as build system reporting and general 
        shortcomings in larger scale multi-project management.
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="27 July 2006 DPML SDK 1.0.0 Release">
      
        <p>
        The DPML is proud to announce the formal distribution 
        of version <tt>1.0.0</tt> of the DPML SDK.
        </p>
        
        <table>
        
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Transit</i></b></td>

            <td>
            Transit is a resource management system that lets you work with 
            uris instead of urls - where uris include artifact:[group]/[name]#[version]
            (for cached based retrieval of versioned resources backed by local and/or
            remote repositories), link:[group]/[name]#[version] which provides an 
            equivalent concept to a symlink, and local:[group]/[name]#[version] for retrieval of 
            local preferences.  Above the resource management layer is a plugin 
            management system that combines 'deployment data' and 'classloader chain' 
            information into XML files that can be used by the system to automatically
            deploy complex systems.
            </td>
            
          </tr>
          
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Metro</i></b></td>
        
            <td>
            Metro is an advanced deployment strategy for plugins.  In effect Transit plugin definitions
            allow for the declaration of alternative object deployment strategies.
            While the basic Transit plugin model supports a generic framework (including antlib
            resources loading) - the Metro system goes orders of magnitude further in its provision 
            for lifecycle management, custom lifestyle, Context-IOC, remote management, 
            logging, and other features aimed at composite component management.  The Metro platform 
            also includes a the 'Station' - in effect a server handles multiple JVMs and provides 
            support for remote application management.
            </td>
            
          </tr>
          
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Depot</i></b></td>

            <td>
            The Depot library provides a framework for &lt;resource&gt; (e.g. 
            jar file, XML files, etc.), &lt;project&gt;, and &lt;module&gt; declarations.
            Modules identify a namespace for a group of resource and/or projects.
            Projects identify a working base directory. Projects can declare scoped dependencies 
            covering BUILD, TEST and RUNTIME phases.  Runtime phases can be further 
            qualified to separate PUBLIC, PROTECTED and PRIVATE scopes.  In addition
            project definitions may include property and filter declarations and (which
            may be direct name/token substitution or feature based substitution - e.g.
            lookup the version of project X and replace token Y with the value).
            The build system includes a command line handler that uses the library
            to resolve project base directories, transitive dependencies, properties, 
            and filters.  It uses the Transit system for all resource management concerns 
            including support within Transit for the declaration and deployment of plugins
            (where a plugin is somewhat equivalent to an antlib plus classloader 
            definition).  Depot uses Transit for loading build templates and antlibs.  
            Depot also includes a small number of Ant tasks that enable build automation
            of the majority of the DPML project.  Generally speaking these ant tasks
            are simply pulling in info from the library (e.g. compile path creation,
            test path creation, meta-data creation, property resolution, etc.).
            When the generic Depot tasks don't meet all of our needs - we simply add extra 
            extra instructions into build.xml files (i.e. its just driving classic Ant).
            </td>
        
          </tr>
          
        </table>
      
      </subsection>

    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>



