<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="niclas@hedhman.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>
    <section name="Process">
      <p>
        Open Participation Software is a new process, and we are trying to 
        refine it as we go along. Please join the 
        <a href="../../resources/lists.xml">admin-dpml@lists.ibiblio.org</a>
        mailing list if you want to partake in the discussion.
      </p>
      <subsection name="Repository Access" >
        <p>
          Once we have established a working contractual agreement between the
          people who are part of the community, we can enable the full vision
          of Open Participation Software, which includes the self-registration
          to get access to the source repository. The idea is that anyone who
          have spent enough time to work out a patch is committed enough to
          be a member (loose term) of the community. It is essentially no 
          different than self registration to issue tracking systems. In fact,
          we have tied the Scarab registration to the Subversion access rights,
          so your username and password are always synchronized between these
          two fundamental systems.
        </p>
        <p>
          We want to get tools in place to make it very easy to revert 
          individual commits that are made either maliciously or 
          unintentionally. It should only be a matter of running a commandline
          tool, which takes a revision number and undo that commit. This has not
          been done yet, and anyone with BASH, Perl or Python experience to do
          this are free to join in the fun and help out.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Coding Standard" >
        <p>
          We have a <a href="code.html">Coding Standard</a> that we require
          everyone to follow. Remember that it is not difficult to write code,
          it is difficult to read it. So the Coding Standards are focussed on
          improving readability, sometimes at the expense that it takes more
          typing to do.
        </p>
        <p>
          Checkstyle is used to validate the Coding Standard, and is very 
          unforgiving. Since Checkstyle was introduced fairly late in our
          history, especially Metro has endless number of failures to comply.
          If you want to join in the fun and help out, it is a pretty good
          idea to start by helping fixing these Checkstyle reports. It gives
          you an idea of how the code is written, and you get comfortable
          with using the Subversion tool.
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
