<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="niclas@hedhman.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>
    <section name="Community Roles">
      <p>
        We are not very strict in the roles at this community, and you can
        basically assign any role to yourself, with a few exceptions mentioned
        below. Below is a list of the formal roles, informal roles and 'teams'
        that we consider this community to consist of.
      </p>
      <subsection name="User" >
        <p>
          The most important role in our community is the User. The people who
          actually use the products that we produce. If the user have a 
          question, it should be attended to as soon as possible. A happy user
          is the best advertising and free of charge. A non-happy user can
          spoil our reputation.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Developer" >
        <p>
          The Developer is the backbone of the community. To become a Devloper,
          you only need to register yourself and jump in. You are required
          to subscribe to the <a href="../../resources/lists.html">
          dev-dpml@lists.ibiblio.org</a> mailing list, and you should also add
          your bio into the <a href="../people/index.html">People</a> list,
          preferably with photo. You also need to familiarize yourself with
          the total <a href="index.html">Process</a>, especially the 
          <a href="code.html">Coding Standard</a>.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Documentation Team" >
        <p>
          The Documentation Team is the heroes of any Open Software community,
          but they are hard to find. Developers will support any documentation
          effort to the best of their abilities, so if you have a desire to
          write, but doesn't know all the details required, please still
          take on the challenge and ask around for the details.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Infrastructure Team" >
        <p>
          The Infrastructure Team is responsible for the DPML infrastructure,
          i.e. the configuration, maintenance and operations of servers and
          applications on those servers. The process of selecting the 
          Infrastructure Team is not yet determined, as we will need some
          constraint on who have root access on these critical resources.
          However, most applications should be configured to be configurable
          through Subversion and operated through web interfaces, and therefor
          allow all developers to help out.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Public Relations Team" >
        <p>
          You can assign yourself to the Public Relations Team, simply by
          subscribing to the <a href="../../resources/lists.html">
          pr-dev@lists.ibiblio.org</a> mailing list and announcing that you want
          to help out.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Quality Assurance Team" >
        <p>
          This is a <strong>formal</strong> team, which is selected by the 
          <strong>developers</strong>. Only people with a strong sense of 
          quality assurance should opt for this position. Only the QA Team
          has access to the QA step on the code ladder, and high level of 
          scrutiny should be done for every commit in QA. If in doubt or
          disagreement, the release process is aborted, and starts over in
          Main.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Release Manager" >
        <p>
          This is a <strong>formal</strong> role, and it is assigned by the
          QA Team. The Release Manager is responsible for the entire QA process
          and that the Production step in the code ladder is in perfect shape.
          Therefor, only the Release Manager(s) has commit access to Production
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document> 
