<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Depot Replicate Task</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Replicate Task">

      <subsection name="Description">

        <p>
        The replicate task provides support for the construction of 
        a directory structure suitable for usage as a repository source.
        The task resolves all dependent resources and copies artifacts 
        from the local cache to a target root directory taking into account
        a target layout strategy.
        </p>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Attributes">

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>key</tt></td>
            <td>Optional declaration of a overriding resource key.
              The default behaviour is to resolve resources relative to the 
              current resource.  May not be used in conjunction with the 
              <tt>ref</tt> attribute.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>ref</tt></td>
            <td>Optional declaration of a overriding resource reference.
              The default behaviour is to resolve resources relative to the 
              current resource.  May not be used in conjunction with the 
              <tt>key</tt> attribute.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>todir</tt></td>
            <td>The target root directory. The default value is 
              <tt>${basedir}/target/replicate</tt>.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>layout</tt></td>
            <td>Set the repository layout strategy.  The value may be 
            one of the default layout strategies (<tt>classic</tt>,
            <tt>modern</tt>, or <tt>eclipse</tt>, or a custom layout
            layout strategy key declared in the Transit configuration.
            If undefined the layout will default to the same layout
            as used by the Transit cache (normally <tt>classic</tt>).</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>verbose</tt></td>
            <td>Sets verbose logging on copy operations.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>self</tt></td>
            <td>If true the artifacts produced by the project will be included
               in the repication process (in which case it is recommended that the 
               tasks be called following execution of the install target).</td>
          </tr>
        </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Nested Elements">

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td><tt>include</tt></td>
            <td>Include additional resources by key or ref. Multiple
              include statements my declared as children of the replicate
              element.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>

      </subsection>

    </section>

    <section name="Example">

        <subsection name="Classic Usage Example">

        <p>The following example is taken from the DPML module build.  The 
          replicate task is used to construct the local system repository
          included within binary distributions.</p>

<pre><![CDATA[
  <x:replicate self="true" verbose="false" toDir="${share.local}" layout="modern"/>
]]></pre>

        </subsection>

        <subsection name="Example using nested includes">

        <p>The following example demonstrates the usage of nested includes:</p>

<pre><![CDATA[
  <x:replicate self="true" verbose="false" layout="modern" todir="${local}"  >
    <include ref="dpml/depot/dpml-depot-builder"/>
    <include ref="dpml/depot/dpml-library-main"/>
  </x:replicate>
]]></pre>

        </subsection>

     </section>

  </body>

</document>

