<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="niclas@apache.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Niclas Hedhman">
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>Email</td>
          <td><a href="mailto:niclas@hedhman.org">niclas@hedhman.org</a></td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Mobile Phone No</td>
          <td>+60 12 2277 953</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Home Address</td>
          <td>
            344-28-2, Vista Damai<br/>Jalan Tun Razak<br/>50400 Kuala 
            Lumpur<br/>Malaysia
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Alive</td>
          <td>since 1964</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Professional Programmer</td>
          <td>since 1984</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Java Developer</td>
          <td>since 1996</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>Civil Status</td>
          <td>Married with one son.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><img src="/images/people/niclas.jpg"/></td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      <p>
        Niclas is one of the founders of the Digital Product Meta Library in
        its current form, and has since the inception been one of the key
        developers.
      </p>
      <p>
        Born in 1964 in Sweden, he has no formal education, and went straight from 
        senior high school to become a software developer at Exomatic AB, mostly
        responsible for the embedded real-time operating system, the EXOL programming 
        language  byte code compiler and interpreter. His career has since
        mainly been as a subcontractor or freelance programmer with process control
        and industrial automation applications,
        including 
        HVAC control (hundreds!),
        district heating control (many),
        <a href="http://www.barsebackkraft.se/index.asp?ItemID=1291">nuclear 
        power plants supervision</a>, 
        <a href="http://www.sintercast.com">composite steel</a> production, 
        <a href="http://www.fagersta-stainless.se">steel pressure roller</a>
        control and many other smaller projects.
      </p>
      <p>
        Niclas started programming Java in 1996, and quickly got involved in
        Java RMI, and was in 2000 invited by Sun Microsystems to be part of the
        Expert Group of JSR-78, Custom Remote References. His work at eWarna 
        Sdn Bhd (2000-2003) with Color Communication and Color Management in the 
        textile industry led to a APICTA (M) "Best Software" and "Best of the 
        Best, Prime Minister's Award" in 2002.
      </p>
      <p>
        Niclas lives, works and enjoys life in Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia. He says the
        relaxed attitude, stress-free environment and low cost of living
        makes Kuala Lumpur a perfect environment for software development.
        The high-tech widget/gadget crazy people, makes the region the fore-runner
        of many new technologies, adding icing to the cake of living and
        working in this vibrant city.
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

