<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@osm.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>Development Tooling</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Setting up the Index">
    
      <p>
      The Depot build system centralizes information about projects in 
      an index file.  This tutorial demonstrates the declaration of a single 
      project and serves as a starting point for the introduction of 
      properties and filters. 
      </p>
      
      <subsection name="index.xml">
      
        <p>
        The following index file declares a single project named 'demo'.
        The basedir of the project is the directory containing the project 
        build content and is the path that the Depot tool uses to locate
        the project's build.xml file.  Basedir values are resolved relative to
        the basedir of the enclosing entity - in this case the <tt>&lt;index&gt;</tt>
        is the enclosing entity so the basedir is resolved relative to the 
        directory containing the index file.
        </p>
        
<source><![CDATA[
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<index xmlns="link:xsd:dpml/lang/dpml-module#1.0">

  <project name="demo" basedir="."/>

</index>
]]></source>
      
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="build.xml">
      
        <p>
        The following Ant build file simply logs a message to confirm
        that it is building.  It contains a couple of empty targets
        (clean and install) which are added simply for consistency (but
        will be used in subsequent tutorials).
        </p>
        
<source><![CDATA[
<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<project name="demo" default="install">

  <target name="clean">
    <!-- nothing to do -->
  </target>

  <target name="build">
    <echo message="Executing the simple project build."/>
  </target>
  
  <target name="install" depends="build"/>
  
</project>
]]></source>
      
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Building the project ..">
      
        <p>
        Assuming that you have the build file and the index file in a 
        directory and Depot is installed - you should be able to start 
        the build proces using Depot's <tt>build</tt> command as shown 
        below:
        </p>
        
        <pre>
$ cd central\tutorials\tooling\simple\build
$ build

-------------------------------------------------------------------------
demo#SNAPSHOT
-------------------------------------------------------------------------

build:
     [echo] Executing the simple project build.

BUILD SUCCESSFUL
Total time: 0 seconds

$
        </pre>
     
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Summary">

        <p>
        When we invoked the build command as shown above - the build tool
        located the index.xml file (by searching from the current directory 
        up the directory tree until the file was found) and located the 
        demo project by matching the current directory with directory resolved
        from the project <tt>basedir</tt> attribute. Once the project defintion
        is located Depot constructs an internal defintion containing information
        about the project name, group, version, properties, filters, 
        dependency information, and information about resources that will be 
        produced by the build process.
        </p>
        
        <p>
        The following totorials deal with the association of properties and 
        filters with a project:
        </p>
        
        <ul>
          <li><a href="properties.html">Adding general properties.</a></li>
          <li><a href="symbolic.html">Using symbolic references.</a></li>
          <li><a href="filters.html">Declaring global filters.</a></li>
        </ul>
        
      </subsection>
      
    </section>

  </body>
</document>

