<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Metro Parts</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Component Datastructures">

      <p>
      A component part associates a component profile with a 
      supporting controller.  The profile provides a description of a deployment
      state of a component type. 
      </p>

      <subsection name="Component Directives">

        <p>
        The default component directive is the <tt>net.dpml.metro.data.ComponentDirective</tt> class.
        The <tt>ComponentDirective</tt> contains information about the component  
        classname (from which the component <a href="../types.html">type</a> 
        can be resolved), a name that identifies the component within the scope of 
        its parent, and a series of directives that deal with component 
        configuration including the assignment of context entry values
        and/or instructions to a container concerning value fullfillment.
        </p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Component Profile Creation">

        <p>
        A <a href="../../tasks/components/index.html">component</a> Ant Task handles the 
        construction of externalized part artifacts based on a combination
        of component type evaluation and information supplied under task attributes
        and nested element.  Once created as an external artifact the part is network
        resolvable and may be easily referenced by application handlers or by 
        components as part of a composite component implementation strategy.
        </p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Technical Note">

        <p>
        Under the currrent implementation part properties are not evaluated.  The principal
        purpose of the properties field is to support a degree of flexibility when dealing 
        with future implementations of the Metro system.  As such, users should assume that
        property names commencing with <tt>dpml</tt> are reserved for future use by the 
        DPML.
        </p>

      </subsection>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>



