<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Depot Ant Builder Plugin</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Builder Plugin">

      <p>
      The Depot Library <a href="../cli/index.html">CLI handler</a> will 
      resolve a builder plugin using the property <tt>project.builder.uri</tt>.
      The Depot-on-Ant-Builder Plugin is an example of a build system based on the 
      Apache Ant product.  The plugin class <tt>net.dpml.tools.impl.StandardBuilder</tt>
      handles the establishment and configuration of a Ant Project using information
      from a <a href="../library/projects.html">project</a> definition. The plugin
      creates a local <a href="context.html">Context</a> object which provides 
      convinient access to project related information such as classpaths, file 
      locations, and project related properties.
      </p>

      <p>
      From a technical perspective the project definition provides sufficent information 
      for the creation and parameterization of the Ant project such that a build can 
      be exectuted without a build.xml file. The builder achieves this through the 
      assignment of a project base directory and a <a href="templates/index.html">
      template</a> build file.  Templates are resolved using the <tt>project.template</tt> 
      property which defaults to the value of the <tt>project.standard.template</tt> 
      property.  If neither property is defined, the default template 
      <tt>local:template:dpml/tools/standard</tt> is assigned.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      During project initialization the the current resource is consulted with
      respect to the types it declares it produced. Each type is identified by a 
      unique type id.  The collection of type ids are used to resolve an ordered array 
      of build processors.  The build processor list is established based on the initial 
      type ids combined with any dependencies declared by respective processors.  
      Finally, the sorted listeners are attached to the current ant project.  
      Targets in the project template trigger init, prepare, build, package, test and 
      install build events which in-turn trigger the execution of sequential build phase
      functionality (such as jar creation, etc.).
      </p>

      <subsection name="Builder Configuration">

      <p>
      The Depot Build is configured using an XML file located using the following uri:
      </p>

      <pre>local:xml:dpml/tools/config</pre>

<source><![CDATA[
<builder default="install">
  
  <listeners>
    <listener name="standard" class="net.dpml.tools.impl.StandardBuildListener"/>
  </listeners>

  <processors>
    <processor name="jar" class="net.dpml.tools.process.JarProcess"/>
    <processor name="part" class="net.dpml.tools.process.PluginProcess" depends="jar"/>
    <processor name="module" class="net.dpml.tools.process.ModuleProcess"/>
  </processors>

</builder>
]]></source>

      <p>
      The builder configuration contains a set of <tt>&lt;listener&gt;</tt> and 
      <tt>&lt;processor&gt;</tt> declarations.  A <tt>&lt;listener&gt;</tt> definition 
      allows the association of a plugin-based build listener to an Ant project. 
      Processor declarations allow associating of plugins to handle specific datatypes.
      Using information for the Depot library, listeners and processors provide the 
      bulk of the common build functionality.  Further customization may be added under 
      a build.xml file or via supplimentary processors.
      </p>
      
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Builder Attributes">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>default</td>
             <td>The default build target.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Nested elements">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>listeners</td>
             <td>0..n</td>
             <td>
               A sequence of build listeners.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>processors</td>
             <td>0..n</td>
             <td>
               A sequence of build processors.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Listener Attributes">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>name</td>
             <td>The listener name.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>uri</td>
             <td>A plugin codebase uri.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>class</td>
             <td>Listener classname.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>depends</td>
             <td>A optional series of listener names (comma separated) that this listener 
               is dependent upon. The implementation ensures that listeners 
               are synchronized with respect to dependency ordering whan attached to 
               an Ant project.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Processor Attributes">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>name</td>
             <td>The name of the type produced by the processor (e.g. 'jar' or 'part').</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>uri</td>
             <td>A plugin codebase uri.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>class</td>
             <td>Processor classname.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>depends</td>
             <td>A optional series of processor names (comma separated) that this processor 
               is dependent upon. The implementation ensures that processors 
               are synchronized with respect to dependency ordering.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>
      
    </section>

  </body>

</document>

