<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Depot Ant Builder Plugin</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Ant Builder Plugin">
    
      <p>
      The Depot <tt><a href="../cli/index.html">build</a></tt> tool loads a 
      plugin to handle project build requests using the property <tt>project.builder.uri</tt>.  
      The default builder plugin (<tt>net.dpml.tools.impl.StandardBuilder</tt>) is an 
      application that dynamically establishes and populates an Ant project based on 
      information obtained from a <a href="../library/projects.html">project</a> 
      definition within the common library. The plugin creates a local 
      <a href="context.html">Context</a> object which provides convinient access to 
      project related information such as classpaths, file locations, and project 
      related properties.
      </p>
      
      <p>
      During Ant project initialization the following actions are undertaken:
      </p>
      
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>basedir</td>
          <td>
          The Ant project basedir is assigned the value of the Depot project basedir.
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>template</td>
          <td>
          A build template is assigned from which formal build phased are established
          The default template declares initialization, preparation, build, packaging, 
          validation and installation targets (which in turn trigger additional build 
          functionality via processors declared within the builder configuration). 
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>properties</td>
          <td>
          Properties associated (or inherited by) the Depot project defintion
          are mapped to properties in a new Ant project.
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>filters</td>
          <td>
          Filters declared in the current project are mapped to global filters in 
          the underlying ant project. 
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>paths</td>
          <td>
          Compilation and test phase paths are constructed based on the dependencies
          declared in the Depot project defintion.
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>listeners</td>
          <td>
          Build-listeners registered in the builder configuration are loaded, sorted
          with respect to listener priority, and attached to the Ant project.
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
      

      <p>
      From a technical perspective the project definition provides sufficent information 
      for the creation and parameterization of the Ant project such that a build can 
      be exectuted without a build.xml file. The builder achieves this through the 
      assignment of a project base directory and a <a href="templates/index.html">
      template</a> build file.  Templates are resolved using the <tt>project.template</tt> 
      property which defaults to the value of the <tt>project.standard.template</tt> 
      property.  If neither property is defined, the default template 
      <tt>local:template:dpml/tools/standard</tt> is assigned.
      </p>
      
      <subsection name="Builder Configuration">

      <p>
      The Depot Build is configured using an XML file located using the following uri:
      </p>

      <pre>local:xml:dpml/tools/config</pre>

<source><![CDATA[
<builder default="install">
  
  <listeners>
    <listener name="standard" class="net.dpml.tools.impl.StandardBuildListener" priority="0"/>
  </listeners>

</builder>
]]></source>

      <p>
      The builder configuration contains a set of <tt>&lt;listener&gt;</tt> declarations.  
      A <tt>&lt;listener&gt;</tt> definition allows the association of a plugin-based build 
      listener to an Ant project. Further customization may be added under 
      a build.xml file.
      </p>
      
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Builder Attributes">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>default</td>
             <td>The default build target.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Nested elements">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>listeners</td>
             <td>0..n</td>
             <td>
               A sequence of build listeners.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Listener Attributes">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>name</td>
             <td>The listener name.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>uri</td>
             <td>A plugin codebase uri.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>class</td>
             <td>Listener classname.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>priority</td>
             <td>The listener priority value. Lower priority values are assigned 
             to the project ahead of listeners with a higher priotrity value.</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>

