<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Archive</title>
    <description>Archive of milestone builds.</description>
    <keywords>DPML, build, runtime, management, components, soa, java, composition</keywords>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Milestone Archive">
       
      <p>
      The following table lists archived milestone distributions published by the DPML.
      </p>

      <subsection name="Build 20051224">

        <p>
        TRANSIT: Includes a registry protocol handler enabling publication of references to an 
        RMI registry in the form registry://[host]:[port]/[path] or the shortform
        registry:/[path]. Updates to the standard log message formatter to include
        the JVM process identifier.  Updates to the ContentModel implementation to
        include the declaration of constructed types used as plugin parameters.
        Improvement to the plugin loader preventing the assignment of an argument 
        to more than one constructor parameter value.  Addition of support for
        primitive arguments in plugin constructors (such as int, boolean, etc.).
        Upgrade of plugin model to include support for system level jar files 
        (e.g. protocol handlers or look-and-feel implementations that need to exist in the 
        system classloader).  Added Enum and ValuedEnum to util package. Extended
        the Construct class to alow references to static member variables. 
        Consolidated all configuration options down to a single strategy
        based on the net.dpml.transit.info immutable datatypes.  Added support for 
        the 'modern' layout strategy which add compatibility with the recent Maven2
        repository layout.  Added the transit commandline configuration tool.
        </p>

        <p>
        DEPOT: Incorporated Janel distribution under ASL 2.0 and added project and 
        copyright attribution to NOTICE.TXT.  Upgrade to Janel 2.5.0 (resolving 
        issues with working directory resolution). Updates to DPML Station with 
        support for multi-JVM deployment and teardown.  Added a remote logging
        services that handles message aggregation from multiple JVMs to the central
        station and support for JVM process identity within the default log message
        formatter. Major cleanup of the profile API and implementation with 
        consolidation around the ApplicationProfile class.  Updated Depot icons 
        based on content from CrystalXP.net and inclusion of credits in 
        NOTICE.TXT. Enhanced the console to support deployment of plugin handlers 
        that add supplimentary content to the system classloader.
        </p>

        <p>
        METRO: General enhancements to the Part contract model including improvements 
        in the way top-level versus composite parts and handled.  Separation of
        state related aspects into a new package 'net.dpml.state' supported by a 
        cleaner implementation.  Introduced support for long-term storage of 
        descriptors and directivies compliant with JSR-57. Added definition and 
        implemetnation of a remote component model and context model suitable 
        for deployment independently of a component runtime (i.e. management 
        occurs on machine 'a' and deployment occurs on machine 'b'). Moved all
        enumerations to formally typed enumerations (e.g. CollectionPolicy, 
        LifestylePolicy, etc.).
        </p>

        <p>
        Please refer to the README.TXT file included in the distribution for 
        additional install details.
        </p>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>Windows</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/20051224/dpml-platform-win32-20051224.zip">
                dpml-platform-win32-20051224.zip</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/20051224/dpml-platform-win32-20051224.zip.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
          <tr>
            <td>Linux</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/20051224/dpml-platform-linux-20051224.tar.gz">
                dpml-platform-linux-20051224.tar.gz</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/20051224/dpml-platform-linux-20051224.tar.gz.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
        </table>

        <p>
        NOTE: File structure layouts within DPML_HOME have been updated.  For Win32 users 
        please note that the bin path has changed to <tt>%DPML_HOME%\share\bin</tt>.
        </p>
        <p>
        Online Javadoc is available at <a href="http://api.dpml.net/dpml/20051224">http://api.dpml.net/dpml/20051224</a>.
        <br/>
        <a href="http://www.dpml.net/reports/20051224/junit">JUnit </a>, <a href="http://www.dpml.net/reports/20051224/checkstyle/index.html">Checkstyle</a> and <a href="http://www.dpml.net/reports/20051224/catalog/index.html">Catalog</a> reports are also available.
        </p>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Build 20050809">

        <p>
        Improvements to Transit handling of dynamic content handlers.
        Improvements to the Depot setup procedure to support version
        downgrading.  Enhancments to Transit and Magic related to link management.
        Internal improvements to Metro enabling mixed component controllers 
        within a composite component structure.
        </p>

        <p><i>
        After unpacking the distribution run the following command to complete the 
        installation:
        </i></p>

        <pre>
 $ depot -setup
        </pre>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>Windows</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050809/dpml-depot-win32-20050809.zip">
                dpml-transit-win32-20050809.zip</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050809/dpml-depot-win32-20050809.zip.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
          <tr>
            <td>Linux</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050809/dpml-depot-linux-20050809.tar.gz">
                dpml-transit-linux-20050809.tar.gz</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050809/dpml-depot-linux-20050809.tar.gz.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
        </table>

      </subsection>


      <subsection name="Build 20050806">

        <p>
        Resolves identified issues with build scripts under unix platforms. Includes
        separation of the checkstyle to a standalone plugin.  Release is synchronized
        with a general quality review of the Transit and Magic systems incororating 
        substantial javadoc enhancements and checkstyle compliance.  Subject to feedback
        this release should be considered as a final release candidate.
        </p>

        <p><i>
        After unpacking the distribution run the following command to complete the 
        installation:
        </i></p>

        <pre>
 $ depot -setup
        </pre>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>Windows</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050806/dpml-depot-win32-20050806.zip">
                dpml-transit-win32-20050806.zip</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050806/dpml-depot-win32-20050806.zip.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
          <tr>
            <td>Linux</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050806/dpml-depot-linux-20050806.tar.gz">
                dpml-transit-linux-20050806.tar.gz</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050806/dpml-depot-linux-20050806.tar.gz.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
        </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="Build 20050803">

        <p>
        Includes a reengineering of the Depot system within which command handles
        are now separated into plugin processors.  In addition of the profile APIs
        have been separated out and included under the Metro package.  Improvements
        have been added for the Win32 platform with the replacement of the depot.bat
        script with a debot.exe.  This milestone represents a solid Transit/Magic
        combination, and improved Depot system (but still subject to change), and 
        an evolving Metro system.
        </p>

        <p><i>
        Please note: following unpacking the distribution you will need to run 
        the following command to complete the installation:
        </i></p>

        <pre>
 $ depot -setup
        </pre>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>Windows</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050803/dpml-depot-win32-20050803.zip">
                dpml-transit-win32-20050803.zip</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050803/dpml-depot-win32-20050803.zip.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
          <tr>
            <td>Linux</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050803/dpml-depot-linux-20050803.tar.gz">
                dpml-transit-linux-20050803.tar.gz</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050803/dpml-depot-linux-20050803.tar.gz.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
        </table>

      </subsection>


      <subsection name="Build 20050727">

        <p>
        The 20050727 milestone is single product distribution of the Depot platform.
        The installation includes release ready versions of Transit and Magic and links
        to a version of Metro.  The Depot application provides built-in support for the 
        install of Magic and Metro.  
        </p>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>Windows</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050727/dpml-depot-win32-20050727.zip">
                dpml-transit-win32-20050727.zip</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050727/dpml-depot-win32-20050727.zip.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
          <tr>
            <td>Linux</td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050727/dpml-depot-linux-20050727.tar.gz">
                dpml-transit-linux-20050727.tar.gz</a>
            </td>
            <td>
              <a href="http://download.dpml.net/milestones/depot/20050727/dpml-depot-linux-20050727.tar.gz.md5">
              MD5</a>
            </td>
          </tr>  
        </table>

      </subsection>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>

