<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Depot Project Declarations</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Projects">

      <p> 
      A project is an extension of a resource definition. A project definition is typically
      used by a build system implementation to harvest information about dependecies, 
      produced resources, and project specific properties.  Typically a project definition
      if sufficient to establish and deploy a embedeed build system such as the DPML default
      Ant-based builder.
      </p>

      <p>
      A project differs from a resource in terms of the granularity of detail associated with
      dependency references.  Specifically - a project can delcare RUNTIME dependencies that 
      are scoped in terms of their rank within a classloader chain.  Dependencies can be scoped
      as PUBLIC, PROTECTED or PRIVATE.  This supplimentary data can be used in the construction 
      of plugin descriptors that separate the classic public API from restricted (or PROTECTED) 
      management APIS from the internal PRIVATE classloader. 
      </p>

      <p>
      Another important distinction between a resource and project is the declaration of a
      base directory.  Typically the base directory of a project is used by a build system 
      to resolve sources and generate build artifacts.  While the project defintion itself is 
      independent of the build strategy, it can provide properties that influence the selection
      of a build system and subsequent build system behaviour.
      </p>
      
      <subsection name="XML Attributes">

         <p>
         The following attributes may be declared on a <tt>&lt;project&gt;</tt> element.
         </p>
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td>name</td>
             <td>The project name (required).</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>basedir</td>
             <td>The project base directory (required). The supplied value will 
               be resolved relative to the basedir of the enclosing module.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td>version</td>
             <td>The resource version (not normally declared - instead the version 
               will typically be supplied using the 
               <a href="../cli/version.html"><tt>build -version</tt></a>
               commandline argument).</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

      <subsection name="XML Nested elements">
      
         <table>
           <tr>
             <td><a href="info.html">info</a></td>
             <td>0..1</td>
             <td>Declaration of supplimentary human readable <a href="info.html">info</a> 
                about the project.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td><a href="properties.html">properties</a></td>
             <td>0..1</td>
             <td>Declaration of a set of <a href="properties.html">properties</a> 
                associated with the project.  Typically property declarations will be used 
                by a build system to qualify resource production behaviour.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td><a href="types.html">types</a></td>
             <td>0..1</td>
             <td>A collection of <a href="types.html">types</a> associated with the project
               (e.g. a jar file, plugin, war, etc.).  Each type declaration asserted by a project
               can be viewed as an artifact produced by the project as a result of a build. When 
               a project declares a type, features of that type (such as the filename) may be 
               accessed by build procedures associated to this or other projects).</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td><a href="dependencies.html">dependencies</a></td>
             <td>0..3</td>
             <td>A project may declare <tt>BUILD</tt>, <tt>RUNTIME</tt> and <tt>TEST</tt> 
             scoped <a href="dependencies.html">dependencies</a>.  Unless otherwise specified the 
             default scope of a dependencies element is <tt>RUNTIME</tt>. Dependencies declared 
             under <tt>BUILD</tt> scope do effect project build sequencing but do not contribute 
             to classpath related information.  <tt>RUNTIME</tt> dependencies are used in the 
             construction of classpath data.  <tt>TEST</tt> scoped dependencies extend runtime 
             dependencies with supplimentary resources used during unit testing.</td>
           </tr>
           <tr>
             <td><a href="filters/index.html">filters</a></td>
             <td>0..1</td>
             <td>Declaration of a set of content <a href="filters/index.html">filters</a> 
                associated with the project.  Typically filters are used to substitute
                string tokens in source code with values resolved from the project
                model (or other project/resources).</td>
           </tr>
         </table>

      </subsection>

    </section>

    <section name="Example">

      <p>
      The following example project is taken from the DPML Metro module. The project
      declares a basedir and the project name <tt>dpml-metro-runtime</tt>.  It declares
      that it produces two artifacts - a jar file and a plugin part definition.  The part type
      is an example of a plugin declaration containing nexted constructor arguments.
      The project includes several dependencies collected under two groups - the 
      first group maps to the projects <tt>RUNTIME</tt> dependencies and second group maps
      to <tt>TEST</tt> scoped dependencies.  Within the runtime group the dependencies 
      in this example are tagged with respect to classloader categories <tt>PUBLIC</tt>, 
      <tt>PROTECTED</tt> or <tt>PRIVATE</tt> (the default). Runtime dependency tags are 
      typically used in the creation of a classloader chains.
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
  <project name="dpml-metro-runtime" basedir="runtime">
    <info title="Metro Container Runtime">
      <description>
      DPML Component management platform runtime container.
      </description>
    </info>
    <types>
      <type id="jar"/>
      <part:plugin alias="true" class="net.dpml.metro.runtime.CompositionController">
        <part:param class="net.dpml.component.InitialContext"/>
      </part:plugin>
    </types>
    <dependencies>
      <runtime>
        <include ref="dpml/util/dpml-logging-api" tag="public"/>
        <include ref="dpml/metro/dpml-metro-component" tag="protected"/>
        <include ref="dpml/metro/dpml-metro-model" tag="protected"/>
        <include ref="dpml/metro/dpml-job-impl"/>
        <include ref="dpml/metro/dpml-state-impl"/>
      </runtime>
      <test>
        <include ref="ant/ant-junit"/>
      </test>
    </dependencies>
    <filters>
      <feature token="PART-HANDLER-URI" id="uri" type="part"/>
      <feature token="STATE-XSD-URI" id="uri" type="xsd" ref="dpml/lang/dpml-state" alias="true"/>
      <feature token="PART-XSD-URI" id="uri" type="xsd" ref="dpml/lang/dpml-lang-part" alias="true"/>
      <feature token="TYPE-XSD-URI" id="uri" type="xsd" ref="dpml/lang/dpml-type" alias="true"/>
      <feature token="COMPONENT-XSD-URI" id="uri" type="xsd" ref="dpml/lang/dpml-component" alias="true"/>
    </filters>
  </project>
]]></source>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>

