<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!-- 
 Copyright 2005 Stephen McConnell

 Licensed  under the  Apache License,  Version 2.0  (the "License");
 you may not use  this file  except in  compliance with the License.
 You may obtain a copy of the License at 
 
   http://www.dpml.net/central/about/legal/
 
 Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 distributed  under the  License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 WITHOUT  WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS  OF ANY KIND, either  express  or
 implied.
 
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 limitations under the License.
-->

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Transit Properties</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>
    <section name="System Properties">

      <p>
        Two system properties may be used to control the condiguration 
        of the Transit system.  One property provides a mechanisms whereby a 
        remote active transit model can be associated as the confiuration
        for a local transit instance.  A second property is available for 
        selection of a transit profile via url (suitable for centralized 
        configuration of static models).
      </p>

      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>dpml.transit.model</td>
          <td>
            If this system property is passed as an argument to the Depot 
            console handler (via the <tt>transit</tt>, <tt>metro</tt>, or 
            <tt>station</tt> commandline handlers), Depot will attempt to 
            locate a Transit Model using an RMI registry.  If declared the 
            value of the property must be in the form <tt>registry[:host[:port]]:name</tt>
            where the <tt>name</tt> value corresponds to a RMI registry name 
            bound to an instance of a TransitModel implementation.
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>dpml.transit.profile</td>
          <td>
            If Transit is not initialized within an explicit TransitModel then
            Transit will attempt to establish a TransitModel using a externalized
            TransitDirective located at the uri <tt>local:xml:dpml/transit/config</tt>.
            This uri can be overridden using the <tt>dpml.transit.profile</tt> property
            enabling the selection of a remote profile.  The uri value will be resolved 
            to a url referencing a TransitDescriptor in XML form (JSR-57).  Overriding the uri
            enables the possiblity for centralization of multiple Transit configurations.
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>

    </section>
  </body>
</document>

