<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="niclas@hedhman.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <title>DPML Sponsors</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Sponsored Links">
      <p>
        The following companies and organizations have actively contributed resources
        to the Digital Product Meta Library, for which we are very grateful.
        If you would like your company to contribute, please contact
        pr-dpml@lists.ibiblio.org for more information.
      </p>

      <table>

        <tr>
          <th></th>
          <th>Description</th>
          <th></th>
        </tr>

        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/ibiblio.gif"
                alt="IBIBLIO"/></a>
            <br/>
         </td>
          <td>
            Home to one of the largest "collections of collections" on the Internet, 
            ibiblio.org is a conservancy of freely available information, including 
            software, music, literature, art, history, science, politics, and cultural 
            studies. ibiblio.org is a collaboration of the Center for the Public Domain 
            and The University of North Carolina - Chapel Hill. ibiblio.org hosts the 
            DPML web site, our resource repository, product archives, the DPML mailing 
            lists and virtual hosting of the dpml.net domain.  Ibiblio have been there 
            supportig the DPML since it's inception and have recently extended their 
            support to include web and virtual hosting of the OSM training content.
          </td>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.ibiblio.org/">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/ibiblio.gif"
                alt="IBIBLIO"/></a>
            <br/>
         </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.berlios.de/">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/berlios.png"
                alt="BERLIOS"/></a>
            <br/>
         </td>
          <td>
            The Berlios project agress to provide essential infrastructure services to 
            the DPML as part of their ongoing committment to world-wide open-source 
            iniatives.  Berlios resources supplied to the DPML include secure SVN, 
            web hosting, wiki services, bug tracking, and operations support. 
          </td>
          <td>
            <a href="http://developer.berlios.de">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/berlios.png"
                alt="BERLIOS"/></a>
            <br/>
         </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.cenqua.com">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/cenquad.gif"
                width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="Code Coverage by Clover"/></a>
            <br/>
            License of Cenqua Clover for DPML development.
         </td>
          <td>
            Clover is a powerful Java code coverage analysis tool. Clover
            instruments source code and then records precisely what is executed
            when tests are run. The detailed test coverage reports help
            developers easily identify areas where the testing is weak enabling
            them write better tests faster. Clover fits into a developer's
            environment, be it Ant, IDEA, Eclipse, JBuilder, JDevelopers,
            NetBeans, the command line, or any combination. Quaility Assurance
            and Project Managers can access important quality metrics over time
            via html and pdf reports. Clover provides test analysis to thousands
            companies and open source projects all over the world.
          </td>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.cenqua.com/clover">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/clovered.gif"
                 width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="Supported by Cenqua"/>
            </a>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>&#160;
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/c/NPOS/10160">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/atlassian-new-logo.gif"
                width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="Issuetracking by Atlassian JIRA"/></a>
            <br/>
            License of Atlassian JIRA for DPML development.
          </td>
          <td>
            Atlassian supports our efforts by contributing their bug tracking
            and issue tracking application, JIRA, to our project.<br/>
            Atlassian is an innovative Australian software company providing
            enterprise software solutions to the world's leading organisations.
            Atlassian's leading software product, JIRA is a bug tracking and
            issue tracking application developed to track and manage the issues
            and bugs that emerge during a project. JIRA customers include
            departments from NASA, Boeing, Cisco, JP Morgan, 3M, BP, Sony and
            more. <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/c/NPOS/10160">Try it</a>
            for yourself today.
          </td>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.atlassian.com/c/NPOS/10160">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/jira_button_120wx60h.gif"
                 width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="Supported by Atlassian"/>
            </a>
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>&#160;
          </td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/jetbrains_color.gif"
                width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="IDE by JetBrains"/></a>
            <br/>
            License of JetBrains IntelliJ IDEA for DPML development.
          </td>
          <td>
            IntelliJ IDEA is an intelligent Java IDE intensely focused on
            developer productivity. It provides a robust combination of
            enhanced development tools, including: refactoring, J2EE support,
            Ant, JUnit, and CVS integration. Packaged with an intelligent Java
            editor, coding assistance and advanced code automation tools, IDEA
            enables Java programmers to boost their productivity while reducing
            routine time consuming tasks.
            IntelliJ IDEA functionality is continuously extended by IDEA users
            and third parties. Check out our categorized list of more than 100
            plug-ins at the <a href="http://plugins.intellij.net">IntelliJ IDEA
            plug-in repository</a>.
          </td>
          <td>
            <a href="http://www.jetbrains.com/">
              <img src="../../images/sponsorship/idea_btn1.gif"
                 width="89" height="33" border="0" alt="Supported by JetBrains"/>
            </a>
          </td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
