<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>About the DPML</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>
    <section name="History">
<pre>
2002

   o An ant task known as Merlin 1.0 was created to deal with the
     deployment of components based on the Avalon component model.
   o Merlin 2.0 adds a formal type meta-info model.
   o Introduction of packaged profiles and hierarchical containers.
   o Avalon becomes a TLP.
   o Development of Merlin moves forward with enhancements to
     assembly automation.
   o Refactoring of Merlin based on feedback from users and
     reflections of the subject of profilable container strategies.

2003

   o The Merlin system is separated into a kernel and assembly engine.
   o The Cornerstone component suite and James mail-server successfully
     validated in Merlin.
   o Merlin kernel and deployment configuration are separated.
   o Improved command line handler is introduced supporting
     deployment of remote block definitions.
   o Refactoring continues leading to the delivery of composite
     component support.
   o Repository support enabled in Merlin.
   o Separation of the activation and composition sub-systems
   o Eighteen months after the announcement of 1.0, the Avalon
     Community endorses a vote for a 3.0 beta release, triggering
     a surge in end-user and developer interest.
   o Alex Karasulu turns Merlin inside-out, inverting the
     kernel/repository relationship.  The repository sub-system
     becomes the resource management solution handling merlin
     bootstrapping, cache management and proxy support.
   o Niclas Hedhman starts asking difficult questions about
     packaging and distribution.
   o Alexis Agahi migrates OpenIM to Merlin.
   o Timothy Bennett start work on jetty-http and hsql database
     components.
   o Several common utilities are factored out and established
     as independent Avalon projects.
   o New and improved embedding strategy for Merlin comes together.
   o December 27, Merlin 3.2 is released.

2004

   o Andreas Oberhack joins the team and brings MerlinDeveloper,
     an Eclipse-based Merlin development tool, out of the incubator.
   o Cameron Fieber submits JMX extensions.
   o Work on security strategies is initiated by Niclas
     + Big improvements in the separation between composition
       model and runtime
     + Leads to a pure model-driven platform and the
       introduction of the notion of facilities
   o Avalon Community endorses a single Avalon Platform Strategy.
   o A JMS facility is added to the suite of container extensions
     by J. Aaron Farr.
   o Work commences on cleaning up the Avalon landscape, focusing
     content and preparing for the retirement of older Avalon
     technologies.
   o Niclas Hedhman and Stephen McConnell prepare a joint proposal 
     for the establishment of an independent project under the DPML.
</pre>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>

