<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="niclas@hedhman.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <title>Open Participation Software</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
      <section name="History">
        <p>
          This thing that we call Open Participation Software started from a
          combination of events in September 2004.
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>
            A lot of internal conflicts at the Apache Avalon project, resulting
            in the Merlin codebase becoming Metro and leaving the foundation.
          </li>
          <li>
            I, Niclas Hedhman, was questioning the need for so much secrecy and
            lack of transparency within the ASF decision making process, and 
            being <em>hammered</em> about not understanding The Apache Way,
            and some challenging me to go elsewhere and try building my own
            community. Apache have been around for 10 years, so we must be
            doings something right.
          </li>
          <li>
            Stephen McConnell mentioning the theory of dynamics within the 
            "Flock of Birds" on the #merlin IRC channel.
          </li>
          <li>
            A chat between myself and Peter Neubauer, 30th Sept 2004, on how 
            to avoid conflict within the new community that was going to be 
            formed around the Metro product family. My conclusion is that we 
            need a <strong>big</strong> flock to counter conflict.
          </li>
        </ul>
        <p>
          That chat suddenly took a turn with the following reasoning;
        </p>
<source>(15:54:02) Niclas: I have been ploying with an idea;
(15:54:58) Niclas: What if the bar to entry the developer group is extremely 
                   low, but that it is equally easy to loose the trust of the
                   others.
(15:55:05) Niclas: Birds!
(15:55:17) Niclas: Where does the flock fly?</source>
        <p>
          A few minutes later the next break through;
        </p>
<source>(16:02:36) Niclas: I think Steve's "Bird Flock" idea can be brought to 
                   something interesting.
(16:02:50) PNeubauer: So basically "I have a patch - Go and ceck it in 
                      yourself!"
(16:03:08) Niclas: YES!!!!
(16:03:19) Niclas: Hit it straight on the nail.
(16:04:31) PNeubauer: I really like that thought - applying the principle of 
                      the outcome of OSS "the whole code is open" to the income
                      of OSS "the whole participation is open"
(16:04:36) Niclas: Unlike ASF, they have a HUGE overhead for a new user.
(16:05:04) Niclas: For instance the CLA.</source>
        <p>
          The discussion then went into practical details, where I elaborated
          to tear down the entire legal framework that is required and holding
          up the OSS movement of today, by going Public Domain.
        </p>
        <p>
          I then had further discussions with Stephen McConnell to see if the
          model had any support from someone I thought was going to be very
          critical and sceptic. He started out a bit anxious, but was quickly
          convinced, which spurred my enthusiasm even more.
        </p>
        <p>
          I mentioned to several other people and all pretty much went "Wow!",
          and that is when I sent out <a href="orig-mail.html">this email</a> as
          an invitation to a group of people to apply 
          <strong>Open Participation Software</strong> to the Metro product
          family that we were starting.
          So here we are, on our way to change the world. :o)
        </p>
        <p>
          All quotes above and in the mail, has been unaltered and contains
          the original spelling and grammar mistakes, but I found it important
          not to alter the content.
        </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
