<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Build System</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Part Based">

      <p>
      Open-source solutions are inheriently risky.  Communities arise and 
      dissapear with a disconserting frequency.  Even commmunities with a 
      strong user community can find themselves abandoned based on little
      more than policital whims. In comparimon - the commercial model provides
      a substantially higher degree of longevity largely due to the 
      organizational and control structures in place.  In recognition of these
      risks the Metro platform has introduced a part-management infrastructure
      aimed directly at risk reduction.  When building and deploying a component 
      on platform version X - you don't want to be left out to dry when the 
      community switches to version Y.  A solution to this issue is addressed 
      though a <a href="/api/dpml/@VERSION@/net/dpml/metro/part/package-summary.html">
      part management</a> archictecture that assures interoperability 
      with a series of low-level part APIs.  Metro deals with this issue though
      the separation of low-level component APIs from the APIs dealing with 
      component control. Componets depoyment infomation published under the 
      <tt>part</tt> data type is tagged relative to the controller 
      implementation.  Controllers are in-turn obliged to consolt and potentally
      delegate runtime concerns to a controller version (and implementatuion) 
      asserted withing a part description. At then end of the day this means 
      that a componet can assert the envoronment within which it is fullly 
      functional - AND - that the components can work and interoperate with components
      built and deployed with controllers with dramatically different deployment
      and runtime assumptions.
      </p>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>

