<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Depot</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>
    <section name="Property Task">
      <p>
      The property task can be used to assign a value of a feature
      of a magic resource or project to a named ant property value.
      The property creates a new property using the supplied 'name'
      and assigns to this property the falue of the requested 'feature'
      from the resource identified by the value of the 'key' attribute.
      </p>

<source><![CDATA[
    <x:property name="spec" key="dpml-composition-runtime" feature="uri" type="jar" />
    <echo message="${spec}"/>
]]></source>

<pre>
     [echo] artifact:jar:dpml/metro/dpml-composition-runtime#SNAPSHOT
</pre>

    <subsection name="Attributes">
      
      <p>
      Task attributes are described in the following table.
      </p>

      <table>
        <tr><th>Attribute</th><th>Required</th><th>Description</th></tr>
        <tr>
          <td>name</td>
          <td>true</td>
          <td>The property to which the value of the feature will be assigned.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>key</td>
          <td>false</td>
          <td>The name of the project or resource that the feature request refers.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>feature</td>
          <td>true</td>
          <td>The feature keyword (see feature list below).</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>type</td>
          <td>depends</td>
          <td>Required when referencing a feature of a resource type (see feature list).
            The value refers to a resource type declared by a resource or project.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>

    </subsection>

    <subsection name="Features">
      
      <p>
      Valid feature names supported by the property task are detailed in
      the following table.
      </p>

      <table>
        <tr><th>Feature</th><th>Description</th></tr>
        <tr>
          <td>name</td>
          <td>The resource name.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>group</td>
          <td>The resource group.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>version</td>
          <td>The resource version.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>key</td>
          <td>The key the resource is referenced by in the project model (the index.xml). 
           If no key attribute is given, the current project is assumed.</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>uri</td>
          <td>The full artifact uri (requires type attribute).</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>path</td>
          <td>A relative file path that can be used to a locate an artifact
              relative to a repository root (requires type attribute).</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>spec</td>
          <td>Short form of uri.  The spec value is equivalent to the 
            uri with the "artifact:" protocol identifier (requires type attribute).</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>filename</td>
          <td>The filename of the final artifact that the resource represents (requires type attribute).</td>
        </tr>
        <tr>
          <td>short-filename</td>
          <td>The filename without the file type suffix.</td>
        </tr>
      </table>

    </subsection>

    </section>
  </body>

</document>

