<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
 Copyright 2002,2004 The Apache Software Foundation
 Copyright 2005, Stephen J. McConnell

 Licensed under the Apache License, Version 2.0 (the "License");
 you may not use this file except in compliance with the License.
 You may obtain a copy of the License at

     http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

 Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
 See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 limitations under the License.
-->

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML CLI Overview</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="CLI Utility">

      <pre>@UTIL-CLI-URI@</pre>

      <p>
        The CLI utility package provides an API for processing command line interfaces.
      </p>
      <p>
        The implementation is based on the Jakarta Commons CLI2 library written 
        by John Keyes and Rob Oxspring.
      </p>
      <p>
        CLI1 was formed by the merger of ideas and code from three different
        libraries and allows most simple interfaces to be modelled.  CLI1
        became increasingly difficult to maintain and develop further and so
        CLI2 was developed with the goals of clearer responsibilities and
        being more flexible.  The intention was that CLI2 would be able to
        model a far greater selection of interfaces and do so more completely,
        validating as much as possible. 
      </p>
      <p>
        The DPML codebase was established in late 2005 based on a fork of the 
        Jarkata Commons CL2 content as CLI2 development with Jakarta Commons
        appeared to have stopped around April 2005 (although posts on 
        the commons list in 2006 suggests that progress may be continuing).
        Modification to the codebase applied during incorporation under DPML 
        include removal of CLI1 content, resolution of a number of testcase
        failures, removal of file validation hidden feature (due to platform 
        inconsitencies at the JVM level), removal of Maven dependencies in the 
        build and test procedures, resolution of issues in the Help 
        formatter, package renaming, documentation enhancements, upgrading of 
        the codebase to be compliant with DPML style guidelines, and additions
        to the argument validator package.
      </p>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>
