<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document> 
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="Freight Train">

      <p>
      "Freight Train" - an unstoppable force that will change the
      way you think about service delivery.
      </p>

      <p>
      The FT is best described as a refactoring of the Metro platform
      that leverages everything about Transit and Magic resulting in 
      smaller, faster, smarter, and better.
      The process kicked off in Kuala Lumpur as a result of Steve 
      and Niclas being locked in the same room for about a month, 
      triggering some really interesting <a href="brainstorming.html">
      thinking, challenges, and generally good time.</a>. 
      Somewhere in this process, Peter, Niclas and I took time some 
      time out on a secluded island somewhere in the South-China Sea 
      during which the "Freight Train" name was born.
      </p>

      <p>
      Six weeks into the process and a number of surprising things have 
      happened.  A working FT platform is already in-place in the DPML
      that is raising some very interesting questions. A description of 
      the current <a href="context.html">Freight Train implementation</a>
      includes information about FT build and runtime strategies, the approach
      taken concerning context management, new concepts concerning internal 
      parts management, and new features such as identifiable instances.
      </p>

      <p>
      Out of this is a set of <a href="observations.html">observations</a> 
      concerning the FT development status.  On one hand we have the effective
      disappearance of a framework in preference to a pattern driven approach, 
      some rather interesting side-effects concerning management, some 
      questions concerning the role of configuration and parameterization and 
      who/what is actually responsible for this, and a few unanswered questions 
      concerning semantic around execution strategies.  Before leaping on the 
      freight train its work looking through the list of obsavations and issues
      to get a better idea of where were are and what needs to be done.
      </p>
  
      <p>
      While my own thoughts on the direction forward are somewhat mixed between 
      the 'gentle transition' and the 'radical jump', I think that there are 
      some <a href="recommendations.html">concrete steps</a> we can/should 
      be taking.  I'm looking forward to all of your thought and opinions as 
      we move ahead on this.
      </p>

      <p><i>Cheers, Steve.</i></p>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>

