<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@osm.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>Version Builds</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Versioned Builds">

      <subsection name="Tutorial Objective">

        <p>
        The default version assigned to build artifacts is the constant
        string <tt>SNAPSHOT</tt>. The purpose of this tutorial is to 
        present the mechanisms available to control default version 
        identifiers and the techniques used in decimal versioning.
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Version Generation Styles">
      
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td>snapshot</td>
            <td>Assignes an opaque version identifier equal to the 
                the constant string <tt>SNAPSHOT</tt> (e.g. 
                <tt>acme-clock-SNAPSHOT</tt>).  This is 
                the default system behaviour unless modified by a 
                command line option of project property.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="opaque.html">opaque</a></td>
            <td>Assignes an opaque version identifier equal to 
                argument supplied in conjunction with the <tt>-version</tt>
                build command-line option.  For example the result of 
                declaring the string <tt>DEMO3</tt> as the argument to 
                <tt>-version</tt> would be <tt>acme-clock-DEMO3</tt>.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="decimal.html">decimal</a></td>
            <td>Assignes an decimal version identifier composed of
            a sequence of <tt>[major].[minor].[micro]</tt> integer values
            where each value is resolved from the respective 
            <tt>project.major.version</tt>, <tt>project.minor.version</tt>, 
            and <tt>project.micor.version</tt> properties.  For example
            the result of declaring <tt>2</tt>, <tt>1</tt>, and <tt>0</tt> 
            as the respective values of the major, minor and micro project 
            properties in conjunction with the <tt>-decimal</tt> 
            command line option would be <tt>acme-clock-2.1.0</tt>.
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><a href="mixed.html">mixed</a></td>
            <td>Assignes an decimal version identifier as a prefix followed
            by the "<tt>-</tt>" character and an opaque identifier.
            For example the result of declaring major, minor and micro properties
            of <tt>2</tt>, <tt>1</tt>, and <tt>0</tt> in a project defintion in 
            conjunction with the <tt>-decimal</tt> command line option and a 
            <tt>-version</tt> option argument of <tt>RC1</tt> would be
            <tt>acme-clock-2.1.0-RC1</tt>.
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>

      </subsection>
      
      <subsection name="Summary">

        <p>
        Using any variation of the opaque or decimal version strategies presented 
        above results in the generation of artifacts with qualtified identities.
        While Depot does not ensure that these identities are unique - developers 
        can leverage the <tt>build -l -consumers</tt> option in order to establish 
        the implications of changes on consumer projects.  Based on this information,
        micro, minor and major version values can be managed (although it is recognized 
        that the overall management of historical published versions versus current 
        build version information is an topic that could result in new management tools).
        </p>
        
      </subsection>
      
    </section>

  </body>
  
</document>

