<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <contributor email="dleangen@dpml.net">David Leangen</contributor>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="DPML Opensource Products for Component-Based Development in Java">

        <p>
          <a href="transit/latest/index.html">Transit</a> is a framework for managing 
          system artifacts and application resources. As a resource 
          management system, Transit provides the foundation for building 
          repository-enabled applications enabling automated classloading 
          construction and dynamic plugin management.
        </p>

        <p> 
          <a href="magic/latest/index.html">Magic</a> is an intelligent build system for Java 
          based component development. Magic provides support for a centralized project 
          object model, transitive version and dependency management, and a suite of  
          tools that automate the processes of building well-structured component 
          solutions.
        </p>

        <p>
          The <a href="metro/latest/index.html">Metro</a> system is a light weight container 
          that provides comprehensive support for the management of composite component 
          systems.  Metro simplifies component management through automated 
          assembly and deployment combined with strong support for the isolation of 
          implementations from the service that a component provides. Metro applications 
          and services are implemented through component composition enabling a building 
          blocks approach that delivers very high reuse and unprecedented runtime 
          flexibility.
        </p>

    </section>

    <section name="OSM Tutorials">

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td><img src="images/info.gif"/></td>
            <td><i>The <a href="http://www.osm.net/training/resources/">
               OSM Resource Management Tutorial</a> provides a fast track 
               introduction to Transit.</i>
            </td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td><img src="images/info.gif"/></td>
            <td><i>The <a href="http://www.osm.net/training/tooling/index.html">
               OSM Development Tooling Tutorial</a> covers the installation
               of Magic, a Getting Started tutorial, working with testcases, 
               module creation and an collection of examples dealing with 
               a variety of Magic functions.</i>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>

    </section>

  </body>
</document>

