<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>News at DPML</title>
    <description>DPML News and Events.</description>
    <keywords>DPML, build, runtime, management, components, soa, java, composition</keywords>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="News &amp; Events">
    
      <subsection name="27 July 2006 Formal 1.0.0 Release">
      
        <p>
        The DPML is proud to announce the formal distribution 
        of version <tt>1.0.0</tt> of the DPML SDK.
        </p>
        
        <table>
        
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Transit</i></b></td>

            <td>
            Transit is a resource management system that lets you work with 
            uri instead of urls - where uris include artifact:[group]/[name]#[version]
            (for cached based retrieval of versioned resources backed by local and/or
            remote repositories), link:[group]/[name]#[version] which provides something
            similar to a symlink, and local:[group]/[name]#[version] for retrieval of 
            local preferences.  Above the resource management layer is a plugin 
            management system that combines 'deployment data' and 'classloader chain' 
            information into XML files that can be used by the system to automatically
            deploy complex systems.
            </td>
            
          </tr>
          
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Depot</i></b></td>

            <td>
            The Depot library provides a framework for the &lt;resource&gt; declarations (e.g. 
            jar file, XML files, etc.), &lt;project&gt; declarations, and &lt;module&gt; declarations.
            Modules identify a namespace for a group of resource and/or projects.
            Projects identify a working base directory. Projects can declare scoped dependencies 
            covering BUILD, TEST and RUNTIME phases.  Runtime phases can be further 
            qualified to separate PUBLIC, PROTECTED and PRIVATE scopes.  In addition
            project definitions may include property and filter declarations and (which
            may be direct name/token substitution or feature based substitution - e.g.
            lookup the version of project X and replace token Y with the value).
            The build system includes a command line handler that uses the library
            to resolve project base directories, transitive dependencies, properties, 
            and filters.  It uses the Transit system for all resource management concerns 
            including support within Transit for the declaration and deployment of plugins
            (where a plugin is somewhat equivalent to an antlib plus classloader 
            definition).  Depot uses Transit for loading build templates and antlibs.  
            Depot also includes a small number of Ant tasks that enable build automation
            of the majority of the DPML project.  Generally speaking these ant tasks
            are simply pulling in info from the library (e.g. compile path creation,
            test path creation, meta-data creation, property resolution, etc.).
            When the generic Depot tasks don't meet all of our needs - we simply add extra 
            extra instructions into build.xml files (i.e. its just driving classic Ant).
            </td>
        
          </tr>
          
          <tr>
          
            <td><b><i>Metro</i></b></td>
        
            <td>
            Metro is a next-gen deployment strategy for plugins.  In effect Transit plugin definitions
            allow for the declaration of alternative object deployment strategies.
            While the basic Transit plugin model supports a simple generic framework (including antlib
            resources loading) - the Metro system goes orders of magnitude further in its provision 
            for composite objects, lifecycle management, custom lifestyle, Context-IOC, remote management, 
            logging, and bunch other stuff that makes for very easy development.  The Metro platform 
            also includes a the 'Station' - in effect a server handles multiple JVMs and provides 
            support for remote application management.
            </td>
            
          </tr>
          
        </table>
      
      </subsection>

    </section>
    
  </body>
</document>



