<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<!--
 Copyright 2005 David Leangen
 Copyright 2004-2005 Stephen McConnell
 Copyright 2004 Niclas Hedhman

 Licensed  under the  Apache License,  Version 2.0  (the "License");
 you may not use  this file  except in  compliance with the License.
 You may obtain a copy of the License at

   http://www.dpml.net/central/about/legal/

 Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
 distributed  under the  License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
 WITHOUT  WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS  OF ANY KIND, either  express  or
 implied.

 See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
 limitations under the License.
-->

<document>
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <author email="niclas@hedhman.org">Niclas Hedhman</author>
    <author email="david.leangen@konova.com">David Leangen</author>
    <title>DPML Transit</title>
  </properties>

  <body>

    <section name="Artifacts">

        <p>
          Each artifact has a unique identifier conforming to the Transit
          <a href="../technical/artifact.html">artifact</a> protocol specification.
          Using a standard extension to the java.net.URL class in the Java API, 
          Transit accesses an artifact through an artifact URI.
          The artifact URI logically identifies a resource and the Transit
          system provides the means for resource retrieval.
       </p>

        <p>
          The artifact URI describes the:
          <ul>
            <li>type of resource (JAR, meta, template...)</li>
            <li>group to which the artifact belongs</li>
            <li>name of the artifact</li>
            <li>version</li>
          </ul>
        </p>

        <p>
          The purpose of the group is to avoid naming conflicts in the artifact
          name space. The top level group should be a distinguishable and well
          accepted name of the organization, and any sub groups to be decided
          by the organization itself to further avoid name clashes.
          It is recommended that the bottom level group is the release level, i.e.
          all resources within the 'release' shares the same version and are
          meant to be working in a group within that version, and not mixed
          between versions.
        </p>

        <p>
          Transit promotes strong version management. The underlying problem is
          that many parts of the system are dependent on particular versions of
          another part or resource, and can not be freely mixed. To ensure
          that all dependencies are resolved against the proper versions, it is
          paramount that a version management system is in place, and policies
          are established. From Transit's point of view, the version is an
          opaque identifier without any in-built semantic meaning.
        </p>

        <p>
          These identifiers disassociate the definition of an application
          from the source of the resources needed to build and deploy the
          application. Meaning, it is only in the interest of the user of
          the resources, be it built tools or running applications, that the
          <strong>correct</strong> resources are provided, and not from which
          server these were downloaded. The task of resolving the location
          is transferred from each application to Transit itself, which is
          configured to know about which servers are available in its running
          environment.
        </p>

        <table>
          <tr>
            <td><img src="/images/info.gif"/></td>
            <td><i>See also <a href="http://www.osm.net/training/resources/artifacts.html/">
               OSM Tutorial on Transit Artifacts</a>.</i>
            </td>
          </tr>
        </table>

    </section>

  </body>

</document>
