<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<document> 
  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Central</title>
  </properties>
  <body> 
    <section name="Claude Bernard Diesse">
      <table>
        <tr>
          <td>Email</td>
          <td><a href="mailto:cdiesse@hotmail.com">cdiesse@hotmail.com</a></td>
        </tr>
      </table>
    
      <p>
      Claude Bernard Diesse is a newcomer in the DMPL Community (2005),
      but was interrested by the Avalon framework technologies since 2003.
      </p>
      <p>
      Born in Cameroon, were he studied in applied maths for computer
      science at university of Yaounde, he left in 1983 for France. After an
      engineering graduate of the "Institut d'Informatique d'Entreprise"
      (1986), and a post doctoral university degree at Paris VI (1986), he
      started a PhD research on IC/VLSI (integrated Circuits/Very
      Large Scale Integration) design and tests processes, in MASI laboratory
      of micro-electronics &amp; micro-computers Department of Paris VI. But
      quit one year later, in favor of enterprise business oriented projects.
      </p>
      <p>
      From 1988 to 1999, he worked for the systems and applications
      developement of prestigious companies and banks like La General des
      eaux (Vivendi) and Le Groupe des Banques CIC, where he discovered
      and appreciated the business world of financials
      institutions. In that period and through varied projects, he gain
      more skills in OO applications development in enterprise's
      business context. He found that despite all huge investments,
      financials institutions systems were not well adapted to to the 
      needs of process change. Also main sub-systems in
      use were technologicaly outdated, and survived only by daily patches
      and scripts supports of last veterans developers.
      </p>
      <p>
      So he decided to design a new smart Banking system for small community
      banks, running on low cost and reliable hardware, and using secure
      internet protocoles to expand their business around the world.
      The hosting environment must delivers high level component based
      development framework, very high reuse and runtime
      flexibility.
      </p>
      <p>
      To make his smart banking system (aka Kasor Banking) project viable,
      he decided to migrate in Canada in 1999. He could then use Internet
      technology access at low cost, and learn more on the international
      banking processes by adding american mangement approach to the european
      way, and so yielding a better process-aware and process-driven banking
      system. Installed in Montreal area as a J2ee application architect and
      Senior Java/C++ developer, he took a MBA degree in financial
      Institutions Management ( Institut of Canadian bankers &amp; Quebec
      University - ICB-ESG-UQAM) from his consultant spare time from since
      2000. He gain more expertise in financials management through diferent
      types of banking and goverment projects.
      </p>
      <p>
      Meanwhile, he was studying existing containers solutions and their
      related development framework, looking for technical characteristics
      such as IOC, SOA, JMX, service, remoting etc.,
      capabilities. Avalon Merlin container seems to give on the paper, the
      most awaited answers. Following, Melin become Metro and now
      propose a new metro/FT version more suitable to his quest.
      </p>
      <p>
      He joins dpml community to work on what will be the supporting
      environment of his dream's project.
      </p>
      <p>
      When not designing or coding systems, he play or coach young guys for
      soccer. He also play volleyball and is auto learning piano now.
      </p>
      <p>
      He have 2 sons who want to be professional soccer players in Europe.
      </p>
      <p>
        <i>His friends call him ... BigDiess.</i>
      </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
