<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <author email="mcconnell@dpml.net">Stephen McConnell</author>
    <title>DPML Metro Logging</title>
  </properties> 

  <body>

    <section name="Logging Channels">
    
      <p>
      The effectivness of logging information is directly related to 
      category naming and utilization of priorities.  The Metro system
      encorages the usage of logging hierachies constructed relative
      to component names (as opposed to static category names).  For example, 
      a top level component named "server" may have child component named
      "demo" and "hello" - the logging channel assigned to the server will
      have the logging category name "server" and the respective child 
      components will be assigned logging channels with the names "service.hello"
      and "server.demo".  Implemeting this approach requires that logging channels
      are supplied to a component (or more specifically - components should not 
      create their own top-level or statically named logging channels).
      </p>
      
      <p>
      The following sample code demonstrates the appraoch to logging channel 
      delivery - the component declares a logging channel as one of possibly 
      multiple constructor argument and the container an appropriately configured
      channel.
      </p>
       
<pre>
<font color="darkred">import java.util.logging.Logger;
import java.util.logging.Level;</font>

public class Widget
{
    public Widget( <font color="blue">final Logger logger</font> )
    {
        if( logger.isLoggable( Level.INFO ) )
        {
            logger.info( "Hello!" );
        }
    }
}</pre>      

      <subsection name="Supported Logging Classes">
      
        <p>
        During deployment the metro runtime will evaluate constructor parameters.
        If an parameter class is equal any of the following log channel classes, 
        an appropriate instance will be provided by the container with a category 
        name corresponding to the component fully-qualified path:
        </p>
        
        <ul>
          <li>java.util.logging.Logger</li>
          <li>net.dpml.util.Logger</li>
        </ul>
        
      </subsection>
    
      <subsection name="DPML Logger convinience class">
      
        <p>
        The <tt>net.dpml.util.Logger</tt> class is a convinience class that 
        simply wraps an underlying <tt>java.util.logging.Logger</tt> instance. 
        It provides support for log-level testing (e.g. logger.isDebugEnabled(),
        level oriented log emitter operations (e.g. logger.debug( "..." )), and
        the creation of new subsidiary logging channels.  More importantly, the 
        class does not expose any operations dealing with channel priority, naming, 
        or other associated management operations (as these are concerns that should
        not be exposed to individual components).
        </p>
        
        <p>
        The following code sample demonstrates a component using the DPML Logger.
        </p>

<pre><font color="darkred">import net.dpml.util.Logger;</font>

public class Widget
{
    public Widget( <font color="blue">final Logger logger</font> )
    {
        if( logger.isInfoEnabled() )
        {
            logger.info( "Hello!" );
        }
    }
}</pre>
        
        <p>
        The following table summarises the logging priority names used in the 
        DPML Logger and their mapping to the underlying Java Logger priorities.
        </p>
        
        <table>
          <tr>
            <td><i>DPML Level</i></td>
            <td><i>Java Logger Level</i></td>
            <td><i>Recommended Usage</i></td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>ERROR</td>
            <td>SEVERE</td>
            <td>Notification of a error.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>WARNING</td>
            <td>WARNING</td>
            <td>Notification of a non-critical warning.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>INFO</td>
            <td>INFO</td>
            <td>Notification of significant application event.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>DEBUG</td>
            <td>FINE</td>
            <td>Notification of internal event.</td>
          </tr>
          <tr>
            <td>TRACE</td>
            <td>FINER</td>
            <td>Fine-grain notification of an internal event.</td>
          </tr>
        </table>
        
      </subsection>
    
    </section>

    <!--
    <section name="Examples">
    
      <subsection name="Example using net.dpml.util.Logger">
      
      </subsection>
      
    </section>
    -->

  </body>

</document>
